Hey there! Have you ever noticed how we just can't stop comparing things?
こんにちは！私たちが物事を比較するのをやめられないことに気づいたことはありますか？
Like, is one phone faster than another one?
例えば、ある電話は別の電話より速いのか？
Or was the movie as good as the book?
それとも、映画は本と同じくらい良かったのか？
Well, today we're going to unlock a super simple English phrase
今日は、そんな比較を完璧にできる シンプルな英語のフレーズを紹介します。
that lets you make all those comparisons perfectly. As, as, as!
それは「as, as, as」です！
So here's what we'll be diving into.
では、内容に入っていきましょう。
First, why we're basically wired to compare things.
まず、私たちが物事を比較するように できている理由について。
Then, the main tool for when things are equal.
次に、同等のものを比較するための 主なツール。
After that, what to do when they're not
その後、等しくない場合の対処法。
Then we'll get some practice in
そして、実践を行い、
and we'll finish up by talking about your new comparison superpower.
最後に、新しい比較のスーパーパワーについて話します。
Alright, first up, the comparison compulsion.
まずは、比較の強迫観念について。
This sounds a little dramatic, but really,
少し大げさに聞こえるかもしれませんが、
why do our brains always seem to be measuring one thing against another?
なぜ私たちの脳は常に一つのものを 別のものと測ろうとするのでしょうか？
Just think about it for a second.
ちょっと考えてみてください。
You're doing this all day long, probably without even noticing.
あなたは一日中、気づかないうちに これをやっています。
From the piece of cake you get to the video games you play,
ケーキの一切れから、 遊ぶビデオゲームまで、
you're constantly checking how one thing stacks up against another.
常に一つのものが別のものとどう違うかを 確認しています。
It's just what we do. And you know what, it's totally normal.
それが私たちの習性です。そして、 それは全く普通のことです。
it's actually one of the main ways our brains make sense of everything around us.
実際、私たちの脳が周りのすべてを 理解するための主な方法の一つです。
It helps us figure out what's what, make choices,
それは、何が何かを理解し、 選択をし、
and just understand our world a little bit better.
私たちの世界を少しでもよく理解する 手助けをします。
But here's the catch. For a comparison to actually work,
しかし、ここで重要なのは、 比較が実際に機能するためには、
you have to be measuring the same thing.
同じものを測る必要があるということです。
So we can compare John's weight to Emily's weight. Sure, no problem.
ジョンの体重をエミリーの体重と 比較するのは問題ありません。
But comparing John's weight to Emily's height?
でも、ジョンの体重をエミリーの身長と 比較するのは？
That doesn't really make sense, does it?
それはあまり意味がありませんよね？
You have to compare apples to apples, or in this case, weight to weight.
リンゴをリンゴで比較するか、 この場合は体重を体重で比較する必要があります。
So, when we have a fair comparison, how do we say it in English?
では、公平な比較ができるとき、 それを英語でどう言うのでしょうか？
Well, that brings us to the star of today's show, the super-useful phrase, as- as.
それが今日の主役、超便利なフレーズ「as-as」です。
Look how easy this is.
これがどれほど簡単か見てください。
You can start with a simple fact, right, like, John is tall.
まずはシンプルな事実から始めます。 例えば、ジョンは背が高い。
But if we want to compare him to his brother who's the same height, we just pop in our
でも、同じ身長の兄と比較したい場合、 魔法のフレーズを入れるだけで、
magic phrase and it becomes, John is as tall as his brother. See?
「ジョンは兄と同じくらい背が高い」となります。 わかりますか？
Simple. Here's the formula, which is super, super simple.
簡単ですね。こちらがその公式です。 とてもシンプルです。
You've got item A, then as, then a describing word,
アイテムA、次にas、次に形容詞、
then as again, and finally, item B.
再びas、そして最後にアイテムBです。
Whenever you see this, it's a signal that A equals B
これを見ると、AはBと等しいという 合図になります。
in that specific way. And what's really cool is how flexible this is.
そして、これが非常に柔軟であることが 本当に素晴らしいです。
It works with adjectives, words that describe things
形容詞、物を説明する言葉、 例えば「高い」にも使えますし、
like tall, and it also works with adverbs,
動詞を説明する副詞、例えば「速い」にも 使えます。
words that describe actions, like fast.
例えば、ジェニファーはエミリーと 同じくらい速く走ります。
For example, Jennifer runs as fast as Emily.
パターンは全く同じなので、 とても便利です。
The pattern stays exactly the same, so useful.
でも、現実を見てみましょう。 ほとんどの物事は完全に同じではありません。
But okay, let's be real. In life, most things aren't exactly the same.
では、それについてどう話すのでしょうか？
So how do we talk about that?
私たちがする必要があるのは、 否定形を学ぶことです。
All we have to do is learn the negative version.
例を挙げてみましょう。 東京タワーは本当に高いですが、
Let's take an example. Tokyo Tower is really, really tall,
東京スカイツリーはさらに高いです。
but Tokyo Sky Tree is even taller.
その違いを示すために、こう言えます。
So to show that difference, we can say,
東京タワーは東京スカイツリーほど 高くない。
Tokyo Tower is not as high as Tokyo Sky Tree.
これで、彼らが等しくないことが はっきりします。
That makes it totally clear they aren't equal.
公式はほぼ同じです。
The formula is almost the same.
最初のasの前に「not」という 小さな単語を追加するだけです。
We just add one little word, not, right before the first as.
この構造は、最初のもの、アイテムAが、 話している特性においてアイテムBよりも
This structure always means that the first thing, item A,
劣っていることを意味します。
is less than item B in that quality we're talking about.
つまり、東京タワーは東京スカイツリーより 高くないということです。理解できますよね？
So, Tokyo Tower is less high than Tokyo Sky Tree. Makes sense, right?
さて、ここでちょっとしたボーナスの ヒントをお教えします。
And hey, here's a little bonus tip for ya.
これらの否定文では、
In these negative sentences,
最初のasを「so」に 置き換えることもできます。
You could say, Tokyo Tower is not so high as Tokyo Sky Tree.
東京タワーは東京スカイツリーほど高くないと言えます。
It means the exact same thing. Pretty cool.
同じ意味ですね。なかなか面白いです。
Okay, enough with the theory. The best way to make this stuff stick
さて、理論はここまで。これを身につける最良の方法は
is to actually use it. So let's try building a few sentences together.
実際に使うことです。では、一緒にいくつか文を作ってみましょう。
You ready? All right, here's your first challenge.
準備はいいですか？では、最初の挑戦です。
Take a look at the words in the parentheses.
括弧内の言葉を見てください。
How would you put them in the right order to make the sentence work?
それらを正しい順序に並べて、文を作ってみてください。
Go on, take a second to think it through. Yes, that's it.
さあ、考える時間を取ってください。そう、それです。
As popular as. This tells us that both sports
"As popular as"。これは両方のスポーツが
are at the same level of popularity. Awesome job.
同じ人気レベルにあることを示しています。素晴らしいです。
Okay, ready for round two? This time it's a negative one
さて、次のラウンドの準備はできましたか？今回は否定形です。
and you've got four words to put in order.
4つの言葉を並べる必要があります。
Think back to that formula we just talked about. What do you think?
さっき話した公式を思い出してください。どう思いますか？
How does this one fit together? You got it.
これはどう組み合わせますか？そうです。
Not as busy as this clearly means that Peter is the one who's busier.
"Not as busy as"は、ピーターの方が忙しいことを意味します。
You are definitely getting the hang of this nicely done.
しっかりと理解できていますね。よくできました。
Okay, let's bring it all home now.
さて、まとめに入りましょう。
We'll do a quick summary to make sure
新しい比較の力を確認するために
you've got this new comparison superpower locked in.
簡単なまとめをします。
So, here's your quick guide all in one spot.
では、こちらが一つにまとめたガイドです。
When things are equal, it's as, as.
物事が等しいときは、"as, as"を使います。
When things are unequal, where A is less than B,
物事が不等しいとき、AがBより少ない場合は、
you just use not as, as.
"not as, as"を使います。
And remember, you can also use not so as if you want.
また、"not so as"を使うこともできます。
It's really that simple. These two little patterns
本当にそれだけ簡単です。この2つのパターンが
are gonna help you make all sorts of comparisons.
さまざまな比較を作るのに役立ちます。
So what does this all mean? It means you now have this fantastic tool
では、これが何を意味するかというと、あなたは今、
to explain exactly how two things relate to each other.
2つの物事の関係を正確に説明する素晴らしいツールを手に入れました。
It might seem small, but trust me,
小さなことに思えるかもしれませんが、信じてください、
it's a huge part of speaking English clearly and with confidence.
これは明確で自信を持って英語を話すための大きな要素です。
So, I'll leave you with a little challenge to practice.
では、練習のために小さな挑戦を残します。
Using this new structure, what's something you can think of
この新しい構造を使って、良い本と同じくらい
that is as interesting as a good book? Give it some thought.
興味深いものを考えてみてください。考えてみてください。
Thanks so much for joining me today.
今日は参加してくれてありがとうございました。